Marck Frience Coto

Experienced front-end software engineer focused on building accessible digital experiences

PROFILE

I am a front-end web developer with 2 years of rich **experience** in the industry. I am proficient in a variety of technologies, including **React**, Redux, Node, PHP, MySQL, **TypeScript** & MongoDB. I am also a strong **problem solver**, a **team player** and an **open-source** enthusiast.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Front-End Web Developer, Shirt Threads

October 2022 — September 2024

- Maintaining the website's UI, refining its design, functionalities and optimizing user-friendly experience.
- Created wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity mockups for a variety of web and mobile projects.
- Developed user-friendly payment methods with seamless integration, customizable options, real-time notifications, intuitive navigation, accessibility, feedback and responsive design.

3D Annotator, Glimmertech

March 2022 — June 2022

Identifying and labeling objects within a 3D environment.
Recognizing and tagging items such as vehicles, buildings, people, or rural houses.

Manager & Graphic Artist, Hube Computer

July 2019 — February 2022

 I combine my leadership skills with a passion for design, creating visually engaging content while managing workflows to meet deadlines. This role allows me to enhance both the efficiency and aesthetic quality of our projects.

Computer Technician, RAM Computer

June 2012 — May 2016

 Maintain, install and repair both software and hardware computer peripherals. marckfriencecoto@gmail.com https://github.com/Unshack https://updated-pf.vercel.app/ +63952-568-8919

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaSript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Next.js, Tailwind, Material UI,

Express, ShadCN, Redux Toolkit

Tools & Version Control

Git, GitHub, Netlify, Vercel, Render, Firebase, Figma

SELECTED PROJECTS

Gallant Homes

An app powered by REST APIs and integrated with Google auth via Firebase, utilizes Node, Express, React, and Styled Components to offer a user-friendly experience.

Eazy Shirt Ecommerce

With React dynamic and interactive components, ensuring the site looks great on any device.

Saasify Application

A fullstack Saas website that helps user manage their online services.

EDUCATION

lligan Computer Institute

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

INTERESTS

Hiking, drawing, web accessibility, coding